# **Bitupan Patowary**

India, Assam

9101625715 | bitupanpatowary5@gmail.com

#### Objective

I am a self taught developer with more than two years of experience and have embarked on a journey of continuous learning and growth in the field of Software Development. Over the past few years I have explored various programming languages and tools. Through practice, projects and hands-on-experience I have gained a good proficiency in writing code, debugging issues and solving problems. I have delved into Web Development, creating websites and Web Applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and also using framework like React JS.

#### Education

Bineswar Brahma Engineering College

 Bachelor of Technology (Hons.), Mechanical Engineering

 Cotton University

 Senior Secondary (XII), Science

 Dreamland English School

 High School (X)

## Experience

• OctaNet September,2023 - October,2023 Web Developer

 Oil India Limited Pipeline Headquarter Engineering Intern July, 2023 - August, 2023

Xcite Org
 Subject Matter Expert (JavaScript)

September, 2022 - October, 2022

• Tool Room and Training Centre Engineering Intern (CNC Milling)

July, 2022 - August, 2022

## Skills

- HTML 5
- CSS
- JavaScript
- React JS
- · Web Design
- C/C++
- Python
- Adobe Illustrator

### **Projects**

#### Shopping Cart

A Shopping Cart with Product Listing, Filters, Add to Cart options with real time price changing with the increasing value and number of products.

Recipe App

An API Integrated Application (EDAMAM) where the user can find any dishes of the particular input of any eatables.

Tic-Tac-Toe

Developed the Tic-Tac-Toe game completely from scratch using JavaScript.

Registration Form

Created a fully responsive Registration Form using React JS where after filling the required details we get logged in.

API Integrated Application

Developed a chatting Application using Chat Engine as the API

Password Generator

Developed a password generator application using React JS which generates a complete random password everytime we

hit the generate button selecting the required length of the password.

Web App

Designed a fully responsive web app for selling gifting items using HTML and CSS.

## Links

• LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bitupan-patowary-2a1ba5162

GitHub

https://github.com/bitucodes